Like many philosophers before him, Schopenhauer tried to understand reality, and it was an evil world he saw.
Animal life seemed horrific;
Most creatures live on hunting, killing and devouring others -
Life was literally a struggle with beaks and claws.
His view of man was about the same;
violence and injustice everywhere,
Every single life was a meaningless tragedy that ends with death.
We live as slaves during our desires and life is a constant tour between suffering and boredom.
Arthur Schopenhauer was born in the German city of Danzig (present Gdańsk in Poland)
and has not surprisingly come to be regarded as the great pessimist among the philosophers.
To understand Schopenhauer, we must take our starting point in Immanuel Kant.
Schopenhauer held on the whole with edge,
But meant that he had made a couple of erroneous assumptions.
Schopenhauer tried to correct them and develop the theory.
Central to Kant's transcendental idealism is the division between the objective reality
.
Of these, only the latter we can have knowledge of.
We can never know what is beyond the human experience.
According to Kant we can never reach knowledge of the objective reality,
But at the same time, it must exist independently of us.
Something (Tinget-in-Sig) must give rise to what we experience (Tinget-for-Mig),
Otherwise, the conclusion is that our experiences of the world arise from nothing - which would be illogical.
Furthermore, he meant that time, space and causality (causal relationship) exist only in the phenomenon world
as they are the consequences of how our brain and our consciousness work.
Here lies Kant's mistake, Schopenhauer said.
If time and space are only the consequences of our consciousness,
Without time and space, the objective reality must be non-material,
because physical matter cannot exist beyond these dimensions.
Another conclusion we can draw is that this non-material reality must be a singular.
For if you remove time and space, you remove the basic prerequisite for something
Being able to be separate from something else.
Even causality is bound to our experience of the world,
Thus, it is not something that exists in objective reality.
From this Schopenhauer concludes that we cannot possibly tell you that anything in the noumenon
Causes what we experience in the phenomenon world.
That we will never reach knowledge of the world by using our senses.
However, we can take advantage of the fact that there is one thing in the world we have direct knowledge of - our own body.
We see inward and try to peel away the physical body (as it exists only in the phenomenon of phenomena)
we find an internal operation characterized by a restless endeavor.
This operational force is at its most tangible during the sexual act or when our
Survival instincts are activated, Schopenhauer calls the "will to live" or just "the will".
All forms of life strive for reproduction and survival.
Schopenhauer therefore concludes that all life forms, like us, are manifestations of "the desire to live".
There was also no fundamental difference between what we call organic life
(animals and plants) and the inorganic (non-living ting).
Everything is manifestations of the will, and everything is basically one with everything else.
The will drives us to constantly chase goals and dreams.
We believe that we will be happy if we achieve what we are looking for, but soon the joy will have disappeared
And the will has been aiming for new dreams and goals.
That's life.
The will drives us further through the belief that we can achieve lasting happiness and satisfaction.
When we strive for something, we do it based on a state of deficiency - we lack something.
We are dissatisfied with the current situation and long for something that is not yet ours.
The volatile joy we can sometimes experience when we have achieved a goal is according to Schopenhauer
Not positive but negative as it indicates the transition from one deficiency to another.
An important source of inspiration for Schopenhauer is the "Upanishads", one of Hinduism's holy writings,
Why his philosophy can be seen as a mix between Western and Eastern philosophy.
In principle, he agreed with Hinduism and Buddhism but did not believe in karma, reincarnation or Nirvana.
The similarities become clear if we compare Schopenhauer's philosophy with the "four truths of Buddhism"
which deals with the cause of suffering and suspension.
They read as follows:
There is suffering in the world.
The reason for the suffering is the desire.
The desire can and must be wiped out.
The road to extinguishing the desire is the eight -fold road.
He represented a pantheistic worldview and meant that everything in the world and the universe was one and the same
- A spiritual transcendent being, or God.
The latter thought Schopenhauer, who was an atheist, was laughable.
He meant that a panteist who opened his eyes to all the misery in the world "must admit that a God who
would turn itself into a world like this, inevitably must be tormented by the devil ”.
Instead of being a manifestation of God, Schopenhauer meant that the world was
A manifestation of the will, a force that must be considered evil.
As manifestations of the will, all life strives for nutrition, survival and propagation.
Because organisms must feed on other organisms,
And all organisms are manifestations of the will, the conclusion is that
"The will must live on itself, because there is nothing except it, and that is a hungry will."
In an attempt to describe this evil and destructive will
Schopenhauer recounts a story from the early European explorers:
“[We saw] a huge field completely covered with skeletons, and thought it was a battlefield.
But it was nothing but skeleton from giant turtles,
One and a half meters long, one meter wide, and equally high.
These turtles came from the sea to lay their eggs, whereupon they were attacked by wild dogs.
With their united strength, these dogs managed to turtle on their backs,
Tear up their stomach and devour them to live.
Then the tiger came and attacked the dogs.
This misery has been repeated since a thousand and a thousand times, year in and year out.
What benefit are these turtles born?
For which crime do they have to suffer this anguish?
What is the point of this horror scene?
The only answer is that it is the will that objectifies itself. "
We will always lose against the will,
But there are a number of things we can do so as not to suffer as much during the journey.
However, suicide is not a way out, as the suicide only follows his operation to die.
In addition, at the moment of death, the will only move to another form of will.
Schopenhauer identified three stages in the fight against will:
Although Schopenhauer meant that life was meaningless and filled with boredom, suffering and death,
he claimed that occasional meaningful moments could temporarily release us from the misery of life.
When we are engulfed by music, or admire a beautiful work of art, we become free from the power of will for a moment.
We are no longer controlled by our desires and desires
And we cease to exist as individuals to become one with the experience.
These moments, however, only last in a moment, before returning to a normal state
of desires and suffering - we are again slaves during the will.
This view of music and art has made Schopenhauer popular with musicians and writers.
An example of an author inspired by Schopenhauer is August Strindberg.
In order to fight the will within it, one must first gain insight into it.
But this is difficult when our brain is mainly developed to satisfy the desire of the will -
- Survival and reproduction - not to see the truth.
Most people will never realize the truth,
And will therefore live as egoists, Schopenhauer meant.
Their actions are performed by self -interest,
And they are doomed to a life in misery, the unattainable happiness was chased.
Only a few will see through the lie and realize that everything is one.
According to Schopenhauer, this insight will lead to a state of compassion and compassion.
If it is only in the phenomenon world that we are distinguished as individuals,
It follows that your suffering is in fact as much my suffering.
But the pity will soon understand the meaningless in his actions.
The suffering is a consequence of the will, and everything is manifestations of this.